If it yells, if it swings, it's got to be Monkeybone!
Monkeybone is a adventure, fantasy, animation film directed by Henry Selick.
After a car crash sends repressed cartoonist Stu into a coma, he and the mischievous
Monkeybone, his hilarious alter-ego, wake up in a wacked-out waystation for lost souls.
When Monkeybone takes over Stu's body and escapes to wreak havoc on the real world, Stu has to
find a way to stop him before his sister pulls the plug on reality forever!
Stu Miley, played by Brendan Fraser.
Dr. Julie McElroy, played by Bridget Fonda.
Monkeybone (voice), played by John Turturro.
Organ Donor Stu, played by Chris Kattan.
Hypnos, played by Giancarlo Esposito.
Miss Kitty, played by Rose McGowan.
Monkeybone is a 2001 American dark fantasy comedy film directed by Henry Selick, written by Sam Hamm, produced by
Michael Barnathan and Mark Radcliffe, and executive produced by Chris Columbus, Selick, and Hamm.
The film combines live action with stop-motion animation.
Loosely based on Kaja Blackley's graphic novel Dark Town, the film stars Brendan Fraser, Bridget Fonda, Chris Kattan,
Giancarlo Esposito, Rose McGowan, Whoopi Goldberg and John Turturro as the voice of the titular character.
It tells the story of a cartoonist who falls into a coma, where he ends up in the otherworldly Down Town where he runs into his titular
creation as he tries to return to the living world while contending with an evil plot to supply Down Town with nightmares.
Theatrically released on February 23, 2001, by 20th Century Fox, the film was a box-office bomb and received generally
negative critical reviews for its characters and humor, although there was some praise for the visuals.
Selick later admitted his unhappiness with the final product and has
since vowed to never make another live-action film again.
The film explores themes of coma, based on comic,
stop motion, parallel world, body-swap.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.